

Salvador Olvera Nava

Full Stack Developer

Ruby on Rails / React - Redux

@ salvador.olvera@outlook.com







salvador-on.github.io

CAREER SUMMARY

Full-Stack Remote Software Developer with a passion for coding and creating responsive web applications with intuitive UX/UI. Extensive experience with both front-end interfaces and back-end databases. I have experience working with remote teams, and advanced proficiencies in HTML, CSS, SASS, JavaScript, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, and React/Redux. 5 years of experience in the tech field as a Mechatronic Engineer.

SKILLS & TOOLS

Front-end

☐ HTML/CSS/SASS

Bootstrap

■ React/Redux

JavaScript

Adobe CS (Ai, Ps, Pr)

Back-end

Ruby on Rails

API Development

■ SQL

Skills

Project Management Lean Manufacturing

Continual Improvement Process

Problem Solving Code Review Git

Linux Heroku Netlify Unit Testing

Wireframing Mockups Teamwork

Creativity Proactivity Pair Programming

WORK EXPERIENCE

Chief Operating Officer

Tridi Mx

2016 - 2019

Lead and supervised daily manufacturing, engineering, procurement, HR, and administrative functions.

Developed annual strategic plans that improved production efficiency by 15% over tenure.

Managed logistical entry of company into Stratasys Global Manufacturing Network. Planned and executed development & management of new global manufacturing lines.

Designed and managed Supply Chain KPI's.

Technologies used:

Ganttic

Python

Google Spreadsheets









Additive Manufacture Chief Officer

Tridi Mx

2015 - 2016

Developed and managed QA system for manufactured good, increasing customer retention by 98%.

Developed and implemented a Manufacturing Execution System, which registered and tracked processes and outcomes of the manufacturing process.

Planned and executed daily production schedules, supervised, coordinated, and evaluated Human Resources to ensure daily production.

Standardized the manufacturing operations processes including CAD file preparations, manufacturing, post-treatments, maintenance, and shipments.

Technologies used:

Embedded Systems Py
Solidworks / Inventor

Python

Google Spreadsheets

Zapier





Jr Engineer

Tridi Mx

2014 - 2015

Researched and developed the post-treatments. Helping to improve the quality of the pieces.

Developed and implemented tools and jigs, with the aim of reducing scrap and ensuring product quality and increasing the safety of the processes.

Researched and developed the improvement of the software parameters and hardware on the additive manufacturing equipment. Improving the visual quality of the pieces, reducing scrap by 10%, and post-treatment times by 15%.

Technologies used:

Arduino Raspberry Pi

Python

on Google Spreadsheets

Solidworks / Inventor

EDUCATION

Microverse Web Development Program.

Full-Stack Developer.

Enhanced my development skills using: HTML, CSS, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, SQL JavaScript, React, and Redux.

Worked remotely doing pair programming with colleagues from other parts of the world, increasing the code quality of the developed projects.

Mentored new developers, helping and guiding them in the coding development. 2020

Universidad del Valle de México.

Mechatronic Engineering. 2011 - 2015

Harvard Business School.

Manager Mentor. 2012

Festo.

Continuous Process Automatization. 2012

Solidworks.

Solidworks CSWA. 2012

AWARDS

Laureate Award for Excellence in Robotic Engineering

Team leader of Mexico team and finalist at the Laureate Award for Excellence in Robotics Engineering, Second edition, 2015.

LANGUAGE

Spanish (Native)

English (Professional)